businessportals.com 2015-04-03

# Privacy Statement - Business Portals .com

### Privacy Statement

  **Privacy Statement**

 By this statement, Business Portals B.V. (BP), sets out how we collect, use and secure the personal information of individuals using any website owned by us.

 BY USING A BP WEBSITE, YOU AGREE TO BE BOUND BY THE FOLLOWING PRIVACY STATEMENT. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE WITH THIS STATEMENT, DISCONTINUE ALL USE OF THIS SITE IMMEDIATELY.

  **What is “Personal Information”?**

 Personal information is information about you that uniquely identifies you as an individual. Your name, address, e-mail address, or telephone number are all examples of personal information.  However, the name, address and telephone number of an individual that appears in a telephone directory that is available to the public (where such individual can refuse to have such information appears in such directory) does not fall under the scope of “personal information as it is publicly available information. Also, in some circumstances, some of this information may qualify as business information which is not covered by this Statement.

  **Collection of Personal Information**

 We do not automatically gather any personal information from users of BP Websites. Personal information is only obtained online if you supply it voluntarily, usually through registering on one of our websites. You are required to supply personal information to view all the content of all BP Websites.  You should also be aware that when you share personal information in public areas of a BP Website, this information may be seen and used by others users. We urge you to exercise good judgment when sharing personal information in these areas.

 BP Websites may use cookies to track user traffic patterns. A cookie is a small data file that certain websites write to your hard drive when you visit them. The only personal information a cookie can contain is information you supply yourself. A cookie cannot read data from your hard disk or cookie files created by other websites. BP does not correlate this information with data about individual users, nor does it share this information or sell it to any third party.  We only use cookies to tailor the visitor's experience to the BP Websites. If you prefer not to receive cookies from a BP Website, you can set your browser to warn you before accepting cookies and refuse the cookie when your browser alerts you to its presence. You can also refuse all cookies by turning them off in your browser. This could affect the areas of BP Website that are accessible to you.

 We may use software that receives and records the Internet Protocol (IP) address of the computer that has contacted BP Websites. We make no attempt to link these addresses with the identity of individuals visiting BP Websites.

We may also use service providers to serve third party’s advertisements on BP Websites or BP advertisements on other websites. In serving advertisements these providers may place cookies on your browser computer and may collect certain anonymous information about your visits to other websites or on BP Websites. This information may include browser type, IP address, domain name and the name of the web page from which you entered such

websites, web activity and time of day. This information is used by these third parties to better understand and optimize the online advertising campaigns.

 From time to time, we analyze traffic and use BP Websites to determine which features and services people like and do not like so that we can improve what we do. We prepare aggregated user statistics or information summaries in order to describe our services to third parties such as prospective business partners and advertisers and for other lawful purposes.

  **Use and Sharing of Personal Information**

 We will generally collect and use personal information to administer our promotions, surveys  and other services, to understand our customers’ responses, needs and preferences, and to generally manage our business.

 We may also use personal information to contact our customers or suppliers with marketing or promotional materials regarding our products, programs and services or to assist our front-line staff in providing tailored sales offers to our customers. We may exchange or merge personal information with data obtained from third parties for the same purposes.

 Personal information may be shared with our partners in connection with services that they perform for us. Our written agreements with such agents and contractors ensure that personal information can only be used for the purposes for which it was shared with them, and that they handle the personal information in accordance with this Statement. Some of our partners are located outside of the Netherlands and, as such, are subject to foreign laws, including laws that may require disclosure of personal information to government agencies in those countries.

  **Your Consent**

 By providing us with your personal information, you consent to our collection, use and disclosure of that information as described in this Statement as amended from time to time or as described at or before the time of collection, use or disclosure, as the case may be. If you do not want your personal information to be collected, used or disclosed in this manner, then please do not submit your personal information to us.

 If you have submitted personal information to us and wish to withdraw your consent to its retention, use or disclosure, please send an e-mail to [privacy@businessportals.com](mailto:privacy@businessportals.com). You may withdraw your consent, subject to legal or contractual restrictions and reasonable notice. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide some products or services to you.

 Where permitted or required by law, we may collect, use or disclose your personal information without your consent, for example, to collect a debt you owe us, to comply with a legally permitted inquiry by a government agency, or to comply with a court order.

  **Safeguards and Retention**

We use physical, organizational and technological safeguards to protect your personal information against theft, loss or unauthorized access, use, modification, disclosure or disposal.  Generally speaking, you can visit BP Websites without revealing personal information. However, given that electronically submitted data is not 100% secure, we make no warranties as to the security of any personal information you submit online, which you do at your own risk.

  **Terms of Use & Changes to this Statement  **

 Your use of BP Websites, and any disputes arising from it, is subject to this Statement and governed by our Terms of Use, including its choice of law provisions. We reserve the right to change and update the Policy and these changes will be made when appropriate, in a timely manner. We encourage you to examine our Policy from time to time to ensure you are aware of any changes we may have made.

  **Access and Contact**

 Upon written request, BP will provide you access to your personal information, subject to certain exceptions as provided by the applicable legislation. If you notice any errors or omissions in your personal information, please advise us in writing and we will promptly correct them where appropriate. If you have concerns regarding our Statement, the security of your personal information or our compliance with the applicable personal information protection legislation, please send a brief explanation of your concern to our Privacy Officer at:

Privacy Officer  
Business Portals.com
